Faculty of Business Administration fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
Faculty of Business Administration fonds
1967 - 2004
F-42
5.82 m of textual records 23 photographs
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
DATES OF CREATION The predominant dates for this fonds are 1967-1999. Five files in Series 7 (Publications) date 2000-2004. NAME VARIANTS The Faculty of Business Administration has undergone a number of name changes that include: Department of Economics and Commerce (1964- 1979) School of Economics and Commerce (1979) School of Business Administration and Economics (1979 - 1981) Faculty of Business Administration (1981 - ) PHYSICAL DESCRIPTION: 12 photographs located in F-42-1-1-08 PHYSICAL DESCRIPTION: 11 photographs located in F-42-3-3-1-28
Financial assistance for the arrangement and description of the records and production of the finding aid was generously provided by the Dean of the Faculty of Business Administration.
Beedie School of Business
The Faculty of Business Administration has its origin in the Department of Economics and Commerce that was established in February 1964 by the Board of Governors. The Department was responsible for promoting research and the development and delivery of economics and commerce programs.
In 1968 the Department of Economics and Commerce began offering a Master of Business Administration program (one of the oldest in Canada). In September 1979 the Department underwent a reorganization and was subsumed by the new School of Business Administration and Economics in the Faculty of Arts. The School consisted of the Department of Business Administration and the Department of Economics. Each school had their own chair, faculty and support staff. In November 1981 the School was dissolved into two separate entities. The Department of Economics remained as part of the Faculty of Arts while the Department of Business Administration was restructured as the Faculty of Business Administration, reporting to the Vice-President, Academic. Later, the Faculty established a Dean's External Advisory Board comprised of industry professionals who provide expertise, guidance, and direction in supporting relevant education and research focused on the changing needs of business and the economy.
The Faculty of Business Administration offers undergraduate, graduate (MBA), and Ph.D. programs in cooperation with various faculties. Curriculum concentrations include accounting, finance, international business, marketing, management information systems, management and organizational studies, policy analysis, and technology and operations management. The structure of undergraduate program allows students to combine academic studies with cooperative and intern work opportunities, and student exchange agreements are in place with business schools throughout Europe, Asia, and South America. The Faculty also offers non-credit programs at the director, executive and management levels. The undergraduate business program is offered at both the Burnaby and Surrey campuses, while the Segal Graduate School of Business - located in downtown Vancouver - officially opened in May 2006 as the site of the Faculty's MBA and graduate programs.
The Faculty of Business Administration is also home to a number of different research institutes and centres that enable faculty to be involved in a range of research activities. In 1990 the W.J. VanDusen B.C. Business Studies Institute was established and funds research on issues relevant to B.C. industry and government and supports an executive-in-residence program and special public lectures. In 2000 the Time Business Centre opened to support research, teaching, and innovation in technology and management partnerships between Simon Fraser university and technology based businesses. In 2005 the CMA Centre for Strategic Change and Performance Management and the CIBC Centre for Corporate Governance and Risk Management opened. As of 2006 corporate support is also being sought for additional research centres including the Centre for Technology and Innovation, the Centre for Building Sustainable Enterprises, and the Centre for Global Asset and Wealth Management.
The Faculty of Business Administration has achieved international accreditation from the Association to Advance Collegiate Schools of Business (AACSB) and, as of 2006, is in the process of acquiring European Quality Improvement System (EFMD Equis) accreditation.
published
Full
Revised
Title of the fonds is based on the name of its creator.
The fonds consists of records relating to the academic development of the Faculty of Business Administration and its programs, centres and institutes. Activities, topics and events documented include the Dean's correspondence with Business Administration faculty and program directors, the greater university community, student clubs, local and the international business community, and provincial and national organizations; participation on university committees; and planning and delivery of projects, programs, and workshops; student intercollegiate business competitions held at Emory and Queens Universities; liaison with the Faculty's External Advisory Board; the Dean's participation on the board of the Canadian Federation of Deans of Management and Administrative Studies; and establishment of international business programs in Asia and North America.
The types of documents include meeting agendas, minutes, and supporting papers; correspondence and reports; annual reports; budgets and financial working papers; contracts; program and instructor evaluations; and publications including program brochures, student handbooks, student resume books, seminar and workshop flyers, newsletters, newspaper clippings, faculty discussion papers, and student MBA project reports. The fonds also includes photographs.
The material was arranged by the Archivist according to the original filing system of the creator. Within each series records have been arranged chronologically.
Love, C. Ernie; Waterhouse, John H.; Shapiro, Stanley; LeBon, Claude; Hoyt, George C.; Schoner, Bertram; Copes, Parzival; Munro, John M.; Herzog, John P.; Photographic materials; Textual records
The records were transferred to Archives through the regular application of university Records Retention Schedules and Disposal Authorities (RRSDAs).
All accessions have been processed as of June 2006. Further accruals are expected.
For further records related to the history of and programs offered by the Faculty of Business Administration, please see the finding aids for the Department of Economics fonds (F-8); Media and Public Relations Office fonds (F-61); Ceremonies and Events Office fonds (F-91); Office of Continuing Studies fonds (F-94); Office of the President (F-193); Office of the Vice-President, Academic and Provost fonds (F-200); Office of the Associate Vice-President, Academic fonds (F-201) and Academic Planning Services fonds (F-202).
Some files may contain personal or confidential information. Access to these files may be restricted as required by law. Files marked 'pending review' must be reviewed by an archivist prior to release, and as a result of the review access restrictions may apply. Please see the file lists and consult the archivist for more details.
A file list is available.
Appendix 1 contains a list of MBA Projects from 1970-1977, listed alphabetically by author. Appendix 2 contains an index to all Access Points assigned to the fonds. Appendix 3 contains a detailed list of all Faculty of Business Administration officers including Deans, Associate Deans, program Directors, and Chairs dating 1965-2006. These appendices are only available in the hard copy version of the finding aid.
- Departmental program files, 1967 - 1999; F-42-1; 1.22 m of textual records 12 photographs; Physical description: 12 photographs located in F-42-1-1-08
  published
  Sub-series consists of records relating to the administration of the Faculty of Business Administration. It includes the Dean's correspondence with members of the faculty and business programs including the Accounting Program, Real Estate Program, Co-op Education Program, Career Management Program, Undergraduate Program, Day MBA Program, EMBA program, and the Caribou College Program; strategic planning and program curriculum reviews; establishment of the Chevron Endowed Chair; constitution revisions; and reports from the student intercollegiate business competitions held at Emory University and Queens University. Records include correspondence and working papers; meeting agendas, minutes, and reports; publications including "Faculty Notes", a weekly news release containing Faculty news and events; and photographs of the Chevron Endowed Chairs.
  - General files, 1967 - 1997; F-42-1-1; 23 cm of textual records 12 photographs
    - MBA program proposals, 1967 - 1968; F-42-1-1-0-1 (Archival box - standard 42-1)
      Textual records
      Pending review
    - Faculty lists, 1979 - 1984; F-42-1-1-0-2 (Archival box - standard 42-1)
    - BUEC report, [198-?]; F-42-1-1-0-3 (Archival box - standard 42-1)
    - Strategic planning, 1980 - 1987; F-42-1-1-0-4 (Archival box - standard 42-1)
    - Chevron Endowed Chair, vol. 1, 1980 - 1987; F-42-1-1-0-5 (Archival box - standard 42-1)
    - Chevron Endowed Chair, vol. 2, 1980 - 1987; F-42-1-1-0-6 (Archival box - standard 42-1)
    - Chevron Endowed Chair, vol. 3, 1980 - 1987; F-42-1-1-0-7 (Archival box - standard 42-1)
    - Chevron Endowed Chair - photographs, vol. 4, 1980 - 1987; F-42-1-1-0-8 (Archival box - small 42-48)
      Textual records; Photographic materials
    - Constitution, vol. 1, 1982 - 1997; F-42-1-1-0-9 (Archival box - standard 42-1)
      Creator's original file classification code: BU.12.
    - Constitution, vol. 2, 1982 - 1997; F-42-1-1-0-10 (Archival box - standard 42-1)
    - Constitution, vol. 3, 1982 - 1997; F-42-1-1-0-11 (Archival box - standard 42-1)
    - Computers, vol. 1, 1985 - 1993; F-42-1-1-0-12 (Archival box - standard 42-2)
      Creator's original file classification code: BU.18.
    - Computers, vol. 2, 1985 - 1993; F-42-1-1-0-13 (Archival box - standard 42-2)
    - Marketing Area correspondence, 1986; F-42-1-1-0-14 (Archival box - standard 42-2)
    - Faculty newsletter: Update, 1988 - 1989; F-42-1-1-0-15 (Archival box - standard 42-2)
    - Faculty correspondence, vol. 1, 1988 - 1995; F-42-1-1-0-16 (Archival box - standard 42-2)
      Creator's original file classification code: BU.16.
    - Faculty correspondence, vol. 2, 1988 - 1995; F-42-1-1-0-17 (Archival box - standard 42-2)
    - 10th Anniversary celebrations, 1991 - 1992; F-42-1-1-0-18 (Archival box - standard 42-2)
  - Faculty Notes/FacTalk, 1982 - 1991; F-42-1-2; 5 cm of textual records
    - Faculty Notes, 1982 - 1983; F-42-1-2-0-1 (Archival box - standard 42-2)
    - Faculty Notes, 1983 - 1984; F-42-1-2-0-2 (Archival box - standard 42-2)
    - Faculty Notes, 1985; F-42-1-2-0-3 (Archival box - standard 42-2)
    - Faculty Notes, 1986 - 1987; F-42-1-2-0-4 (Archival box - standard 42-2)
    - FacTalk, 1988 - 1991; F-42-1-2-0-5 (Archival box - standard 42-2)
  - Curriculum review, 1991 - 1992; F-42-1-3; 7 cm of textual records
    - Curriculum review - general, 1991 - 1992; F-42-1-3-0-1 (Archival box - small 42-3)
    - Curriculum review - BBA, 1991 - 1992; F-42-1-3-0-2 (Archival box - small 42-3)
    - Curriculum review - DMBA, 1991 - 1992; F-42-1-3-0-3 (Archival box - small 42-3)
    - Curriculum review - EMBA, 1991 - 1992; F-42-1-3-0-4 (Archival box - small 42-3)
  - Student intercollegiate business competitions, 1969 - 1997; F-42-1-4; 38 cm of textual records
    Queen's University; Emory University
    - Queens/Emory team members and summary reports, 1969 - 1987; F-42-1-4-0-1 (Archival box - standard 42-4)
    - Emory competition, 1971; F-42-1-4-0-2 (Archival box - standard 42-4)
    - Emory competition, 1975; F-42-1-4-0-3 (Archival box - standard 42-4)
    - Emory competition, 1977; F-42-1-4-0-4 (Archival box - standard 42-4)
    - Emory competition, 1978; F-42-1-4-0-5 (Archival box - standard 42-4)
    - Emory competition, 1979; F-42-1-4-0-6 (Archival box - standard 42-4)
    - Emory competition, 1980; F-42-1-4-0-7 (Archival box - standard 42-4)
    - Emory competition, vol. 1, 1980 - 1981; F-42-1-4-0-8 (Archival box - standard 42-4)
    - Emory competition, vol. 2, 1980 - 1981; F-42-1-4-0-9 (Archival box - standard 42-4)
    - Newspaper clippings about SFU, 1980 - 1994; F-42-1-4-0-10 (Archival box - standard 42-5)
    - Review Board - Emory/Queens, 1981; F-42-1-4-0-11 (Archival box - standard 42-5)
    - Emory competition, vol. 1, 1981 - 1982; F-42-1-4-0-12 (Archival box - standard 42-5)
    - Emory competition, vol. 2, 1981 - 1982; F-42-1-4-0-13 (Archival box - standard 42-5)
    - Queens competition, 1982 - 1983; F-42-1-4-0-14 (Archival box - standard 42-5)
    - Emory competition, vol. 1, 1982 - 1983; F-42-1-4-0-15 (Archival box - standard 42-5)
    - Emory competition, vol. 2, 1982 - 1983; F-42-1-4-0-16 (Archival box - standard 42-5)
    - Queens competition, 1983; F-42-1-4-0-17 (Archival box - standard 42-5)
    - Emory competition, 1983; F-42-1-4-0-18 (Archival box - standard 42-5)
    - Arbitration cases and submissions, 1983 - 1987; F-42-1-4-0-19 (Archival box - standard 42-5)
    - Queens competition, 1984 - 1986; F-42-1-4-0-20 (Archival box - standard 42-5)
    - Queens competition, 1985; F-42-1-4-0-21 (Archival box - standard 42-5)
    - Queens competition, 1986; F-42-1-4-0-22 (Archival box - standard 42-5)
    - Emory competition, vol. 1, 1986 - 1987; F-42-1-4-0-23 (Archival box - standard 42-6)
    - Emory competition, vol. 2, 1986 - 1987; F-42-1-4-0-24 (Archival box - standard 42-6)
    - Queens competition, vol. 1, 1986 - 1987; F-42-1-4-0-25 (Archival box - standard 42-6)
    - Queens competition, vol. 2, 1986 - 1987; F-42-1-4-0-26 (Archival box - standard 42-6)
    - Student Intercollegiate Business Games, vol. 1, 1987 - 1997; F-42-1-4-0-27 (Archival box - standard 42-6)
    - Student Intercollegiate Business Games, vol. 2, 1987 - 1997; F-42-1-4-0-28 (Archival box - standard 42-6)
  - Business Administration programs, 1984 - 1999; F-42-1-5; 50 cm of textual records
    - Accounting program, 1984 - 1993; F-42-1-5-1; 3 cm of textual records
      - Correspondence and reports, 1984 - 1988; F-42-1-5-1-1 (Archival box - standard 42-7)
        Creator's original file classification code: BU.1.
      - Correspondence and reports, 1989 - 1993; F-42-1-5-1-2 (Archival box - standard 42-7)
    - Real Estate program, 1991 - 1995; F-42-1-5-2; 3 cm of textual records
      - Program proposal, vol. 1, 1991 - 1995; F-42-1-5-2-1 (Archival box - standard 42-7)
        Creator's original file classification code: BU.27.
      - Program proposal, vol. 2, 1991 - 1995; F-42-1-5-2-1 (Archival box - standard 42-7)
    - Co-Op Education program, 1985 - 1994; F-42-1-5-3; 3 cm of textual records
      - Correspondence and reports, 1985 - 1988; F-42-1-5-3-1 (Archival box - standard 42-7)
        Creator's original file classification code: BU.10.
      - Correspondence and reports, 1989 - 1994; F-42-1-5-3-2 (Archival box - standard 42-7)
    - Career Management program, 1994 - 1996; F-42-1-5-4; 3 cm of textual records
      - Correspondence and reports, 1994 - 1996; F-42-1-5-4-1 (Archival box - standard 42-7)
      - Program textbook, 1995; F-42-1-5-4-2 (Archival box - standard 42-7)
    - Undergraduate program, 1988 - 1999; F-42-1-5-5; 13 cm of textual records
      - Correspondence and reports, 1988 - 1989; F-42-1-5-5-1 (Archival box - standard 42-8)
        Creator's original file classification code: BU.9.
      - Correspondence and reports, 1990 - 1991; F-42-1-5-5-2 (Archival box - standard 42-8)
      - Correspondence and reports, 1992; F-42-1-5-5-3 (Archival box - standard 42-8)
      - Correspondence and reports, 1993; F-42-1-5-5-4 (Archival box - standard 42-8)
      - Correspondence and reports, 1994 - 1996; F-42-1-5-5-5 (Archival box - standard 42-8)
      - Correspondence and reports, 1997; F-42-1-5-5-6 (Archival box - standard 42-8)
      - Correspondence and reports, 1998 - 1999; F-42-1-5-5-7 (Archival box - standard 42-8)
    - MBA (Day) program, 1986 - 1998; F-42-1-5-6; 13 cm of textual records
      - Correspondence and reports, 1986 - 1987; F-42-1-5-6-1 (Archival box - standard 42-9)
        Creator's original file classification code: BU.7.
      - Correspondence and reports, 1988; F-42-1-5-6-2 (Archival box - standard 42-9)
      - Correspondence and reports, 1989; F-42-1-5-6-3 (Archival box - standard 42-9)
      - Correspondence and reports, 1990; F-42-1-5-6-4 (Archival box - standard 42-9)
      - Correspondence and reports, 1991; F-42-1-5-6-5 (Archival box - standard 42-9)
      - Correspondence and reports, 1992; F-42-1-5-6-6 (Archival box - standard 42-9)
      - Correspondence and reports, 1993; F-42-1-5-6-7 (Archival box - standard 42-9)
      - Correspondence and reports, 1994; F-42-1-5-6-8 (Archival box - standard 42-9)
      - Correspondence and reports, 1995; F-42-1-5-6-9 (Archival box - standard 42-9)
      - Correspondence and reports, 1996; F-42-1-5-6-10 (Archival box - standard 42-9)
      - Correspondence and reports, 1997; F-42-1-5-6-11 (Archival box - standard 42-9)
      - Correspondence and reports, 1998; F-42-1-5-6-12 (Archival box - standard 42-9)
    - EMBA program - Harbour Centre, 1989 - 1996; F-42-1-5-7; 10 cm of textual records
      - Correspondence and reports, 1989; F-42-1-5-7-1 (Archival box - standard 42-10)
        Creator's original file classification code: BU.8.
      - Correspondence and reports, 1990; F-42-1-5-7-2 (Archival box - standard 42-10)
      - Correspondence and reports, 1991; F-42-1-5-7-3 (Archival box - standard 42-10)
      - Correspondence and reports, 1992; F-42-1-5-7-4 (Archival box - standard 42-10)
      - Correspondence and reports, 1993; F-42-1-5-7-5 (Archival box - standard 42-10)
      - Correspondence and reports, 1994; F-42-1-5-7-6 (Archival box - standard 42-10)
      - Correspondence and reports, 1995; F-42-1-5-7-7 (Archival box - standard 42-10)
      - Correspondence and reports, 1996; F-42-1-5-7-8 (Archival box - standard 42-10)
    - Caribou College program, 1989 - 1991; F-42-1-5-8; 3 cm of textual records
      Caribou College
      - Correspondence and reports, 1989; F-42-1-5-8-1 (Archival box - standard 42-10)
      - Correspondence and reports, 1990 - 1991; F-42-1-5-8-2 (Archival box - standard 42-10)
- Financial records, 1983 - 1995; F-42-2; 17 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records relating to the financial operation of the Faculty of Business Administration and includes an external review of the Accounting area; short and long-term budget planning; budget plan applications; operating budget statistics and reports; funding applications for projects; and staff allocation funding. Records include correspondence, budgets, reports, and financial working papers.
  - Accounting area - external review, 1983 - 1984; F-42-2-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 42-11)
  - Budget correspondence and reports, 1987; F-42-2-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 42-11)
  - Budget correspondence and reports, 1988; F-42-2-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 42-11)
  - Budget correspondence and reports, 1989; F-42-2-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 42-11)
  - Budget correspondence and reports, 1990; F-42-2-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 42-11)
  - Budget correspondence and reports, 1991; F-42-2-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 42-11)
  - Budget correspondence and reports, 1992; F-42-2-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 42-11)
  - Budget correspondence and reports, 1993; F-42-2-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 42-12)
  - Budget correspondence and reports, 1994; F-42-2-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 42-12)
  - Budget correspondence and reports, 1995; F-42-2-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 42-12)
- Centres and Institute files, 1984 - 1994; F-42-3; 84 cm of textual records 11 photographs
  Series consists of records relating to the development and administration of the Centre for North American Business Studies at Harbour Centre; the Asia Pacific Business Institute, a joint venture between UBC, SFU and UVic; and the Enterprise Centre. Activities and topics documented include the Dean's correspondence with board members and business partners; proposals and funding applications; development of seminars and workshops; budget planning; staffing requirements; and program evaluations. Also included are records related to the Student Entrepreneur program and Starting Right the First Time program. Records include correspondence, working papers, reports, agendas and minutes, budget reports and financial statements, annual reports, legal contracts, newspaper clippings, publications, and photographs.
  For additional records related to the Asia Pacific Business Institute, contact the University of British Columbia Archives which holds the Asia Pacific Business Institute fonds (1984-1988).
  - Centre for North American Business Studies (CNABS), 1988 - 1994; F-42-3-1; 13 cm of textual records
    Centre for North American Business Studies
    - Correspondence and reports, 1988 - 1989; F-42-3-1-0-1 (Archival box - standard 42-12)
      Creator's original file classification code: C.5.
    - Correspondence and reports, 1990; F-42-3-1-0-2 (Archival box - standard 42-12)
    - Correspondence and reports, 1991; F-42-3-1-0-3 (Archival box - standard 42-12)
    - Correspondence and reports, vol. 1, 1992; F-42-3-1-0-4 (Archival box - standard 42-12)
    - Correspondence and reports, vol. 2, 1992; F-42-3-1-0-5 (Archival box - standard 42-12)
    - Correspondence and reports, vol. 1, 1993; F-42-3-1-0-6 (Archival box - standard 42-12)
    - Correspondence and reports, vol. 2, 1993; F-42-3-1-0-7 (Archival box - standard 42-13)
    - Correspondence and reports, vol. 1, 1994; F-42-3-1-0-8 (Archival box - standard 42-13)
    - Correspondence and reports, vol. 2, 1994; F-42-3-1-0-9 (Archival box - standard 42-13)
  - Asia Pacific Business Institute, 1985 - 1987; F-42-3-2; 9 cm of textual records
    - Correspondence and reports, vol. 1, 1985; F-42-3-2-0-1 (Archival box - standard 42-13)
    - Correspondence and reports, vol. 2, 1985; F-42-3-2-0-2 (Archival box - standard 42-13)
    - Correspondence and reports, vol. 1, 1986; F-42-3-2-0-3 (Archival box - standard 42-13)
    - Correspondence and reports, vol. 2, 1986; F-42-3-2-0-4 (Archival box - standard 42-13)
    - Correspondence and reports, vol. 3, 1986; F-42-3-2-0-5 (Archival box - standard 42-13)
    - Correspondence and reports, 1987; F-42-3-2-0-6 (Archival box - standard 42-14)
  - Enterprise Centre, 1984 - 1991; F-42-3-3; 62 cm of textual records 11 photographs; Physical description: 11 photographs located in F-42-3-3-1-28
    - Enterprise Centre - administrative records, 1984 - 1991; F-42-3-3-1; 30 cm of textual records; Physical description: 11 photographs located in F-42-3-3-1-28
      Student Enterprise Club; Entrepreneur's Club
      - Background information, 1984; F-42-3-3-1-1 (Archival box - standard 42-14)
      - Reports, 1984 - 1985; F-42-3-3-1-2 (Archival box - standard 42-14)
      - Correspondence and reports, vol. 1, 1984 - 1986; F-42-3-3-1-3 (Archival box - standard 42-14)
      - Correspondence and reports, vol. 2, 1984 - 1986; F-42-3-3-1-4 (Archival box - standard 42-14)
      - Development, 1985; F-42-3-3-1-5 (Archival box - standard 42-14)
      - Industrial Liaison Office university/ industry technology transfer, 1985; F-42-3-3-1-6 (Archival box - standard 42-14)
      - Action Plan, 1986; F-42-3-3-1-7 (Archival box - standard 42-14)
      - History of Enterprise Centre, 1986; F-42-3-3-1-8 (Archival box - standard 42-14)